Bharti Patel, Senior Consultant (Sr. Product Designer)

I'm a designer passionate about creativity and using design and technology to create a meaningful change in people's lives. I love the challenge of taking something complex and making easy to use. I believe that simplicity is the ultimate sophistication – that less is more. I have an extensive background in graphic design, web design, and advertising. I bring my experience, passion, and professionalism to any creative task or project.

Skills & Expertise:

- Adobe Creative Suite
- Sketch & Figma
- InVision
- Axure
- Agile Environment
- Oracle Commerce Cloude(OCC)
- Zeplin
- User Research
- Journey Mapping & User Personas
- Rapid Prototype
- Information Architecture
- Usability Testing

Education:

Commercial Arts, (Graphic Design & Visual Design)

Nirmala Niketan College

Certifications

General Assembly – **UXDi**

Academy X – Web Design

Learn IT – Computer Graphics

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Apex IT – Fremont, CA
Senior Product Designer

July 2021 - Aug 2023

- Working as an in-house Sr. Consultant (Sr. Product Designer) Theorem at Apex IT, a global consulting firm that provides award-winning services to transform the customer, employee, and student experiences.
- Experience solving business problems designing for a range of different brands and touchpoints. I bring a human-centered focus that drives creative, meaningful, user-friendly solutions. I have worked across a range of design disciplines both in-house and with various Apex IT clients. I'm passionate about human behavior, ethics, and solving complex problem spaces for businesses.
- Produce concept briefs and prototypes while collaborating with cross-functional teams and various stakeholders.
- Helped the team to execute solutions based on UX goals and priorities using tools like Sketch prototyping them using the InVision app and, delivering pixel-perfect mockups for development. And have experience driving design through the full product development cycle (discovery, concepts, prototypes, specs)

IL-DCEO Weatherization

Lead Product Designer

- The IL-DCEO Weatherization project is a complete solution for managing needs-based Weatherization programs for residents of
 the state of Illinois. The solution includes end-to-end program management from intake and eligibility, to energy auditing to
 identify home energy improvement opportunities along with return on investment calculations for government compliance. The
 solution also manages grants, budgeting, and funds tracking as well as contractor management, QA controls for rules-based
 compliance, and QA tools including in-progress, final, and QA inspections.
- Worked as Lead Product designer for ILDCEO OEC & VBCS Cloud Implementation platform. This project included multiple app
 designs and end-to-end experience including, Catalog, Work Order, Inspection, Budget, and programmatic Monitoring (Survey
 Tool). Helped the project in terms of holistic design, applied strategic thinking and business goals to design work, focused on
 usability, and understood aesthetic values.
- Develop smooth and pixel-precise user experiences across web, mobile web, and native apps (IOS and Android)
- Develop intuitive, usable, and engaging interactions and visual designs for mobile and desktop including dealing with platform rules, and guidelines.
- Gather requirements around functionality and translate those requirements into elegant functional solutions.
- Work in the agile environment i.e. scrums, sprints, reviews, planning, etc.

- Collaborated daily with design workshops with Product Owners & and Principle architects, from concept to spec delivery. Develop
 multiple comps to show different potential designs & translate customer needs into design and articulate that design to technical
 and non-technical team members.
- Support the product development process with wireframes, user flows, journey maps, high-fidelity mockups, interactive
 prototypes, and evaluative research.
- Package up the red specs, style guide, and graphic elements and make them available to the implementation team.

Oshkosh Corporation https://parts.oshkoshsnowproducts.com

Sr. Product Designer

- Worked as Sr. Product Designer for Oshkosh Snow Commerce OCC & OCM Cloud Implementation B2B platform. This project is to
 assist the Oshkosh Snow Aftermarket group in transitioning from manual customer ordering processes to an online storefront
 utilizing Oracle Commerce Cloud.
- Facilitating design thinking workshops or design sprints with peers, and stakeholders.
- Collaborated on day-to-day biases with Product Owners, Principle architects, program managers, directors & and developers from concept to spec delivery. Develop multiple comps to show different potential designs
- Worked closely with the team to apply intuitive, usable, and engaging interactions and visual designs to desktop & and mobile interfaces.
- Collaborated with team & and came up with creative ideas, followed the latest standards, the trend in web, mobile, and native apps (iOS and Android)
- Support the product development process with wireframes, user flows, journey maps, high-fidelity mockups, interactive prototypes, and evaluative research.
- Package up the red specs, style guide, and graphic elements and make them available to the implementation team.

Mutual Materials https://business.mutualmaterials.com/

Senior Product Designer

- Worked as the sole designer for Mutual Materials eCommerce B2B platform. This was a new addition to their retail E-commerce site that their vendors(business partners) have access. Its business model is to sell construction materials via their B2B channel partners/customers. As a Product designer helped with research and end-to-end flow with a holistic experience.
- Collaborated on a day-to-day basis with Product Owners, Principle architects, & and developers from concept to spec delivery.
- Created a style guide, that was needed following the brand guidelines that the company has.
- Package up the style guide and graphic elements and make them available to the implementation team.
- Helping the Support team with the second phase implementation with an enhancement that got from user testing.

McNeilus Companies, Inc https://www.refuse.streetsmartparts.com/

Sr. Product Designer

- Worked as a Product designer for Mcneilus/Street Smart parts E-comm B2B platform. This project is the redesign of an existing site that brings a human-centered focus that drives creative, meaningful, user-friendly solutions.
- Collaborated on a day-to-day basis with Product Owners, Principle architects, program managers, directors & and developers from concept to spec delivery. Develop multiple comps to show different potential designs
- Led design review sessions with the client's core team and internal team. Refined designs as needed based on feedback. Updated concept prototype with selected visual look desired following brand guidelines that the company has.
- Package up the red specs, style guide, and graphic elements and make them available to the implementation team.

The Michaels Companies, Inc.

Mar 2020 - July 2020

UX Designer

- Worked with the E-comm team for Michaels.com and the native app on improving user experience.
- Produced concept briefs prototypes and UX designs while collaborating with engineering and product management.
- Worked on curbside pickup, checkout streamlining & and shipping options concept designs by conducting market research and competitive landscape analyses.

San Jose State University UI/UX Designer

Aug 2019 - Sept 2019

- Worked with the team as a UX/Visual/UI designer to create a new advanced analytics platform.
- Worked on landing page and other page designs to make it more simpler and user-friendly from complex and abstract material following SJSU brand guidelines.
- Produced mockups and prototypes while iterating with engineering and product management to meet feature requirements for the existing product.

Cisco Systems

July 2018 – Oct 2018

. UI/UX Designer

- Worked with the team as a UX/UI designer for the web application, determining the best UX solutions based on customer feedback & and business goals. Identifying challenges and adapting as needed based on the context of the solution and customer.
- Created pixel-perfect mocks to communicate user flow interaction and visual designs. Delivered redline specs for development following Cisco brand guidelines.
- Collaborated with PMs, developers & and engineers from conception to early implementation establishing timelines and consensus from all parties around product flow.

12 Digit Marketing

June 2017 - Oct 2017

UI/UX Designer

- Worked with a team to improve UI and, provide the right solution to the interface and, deliver pixel-perfect mockups for development.
- Producing mockups and prototypes while iterating with engineering and product management to meet feature requirements for the existing product.
- Worked with Client Service Manager/Marketing with visual designs for Retail/Brand creative campaigns delivering responsive designs.

Cisco Systems

Jan 2017 - May 2017

UX Designer & Visual Designer

- Worked as one of the UX designers and visual Designers for the Cisco VTS (Virtual Topology Systems) product.
- Worked on design to be simpler and user-friendly from complex and abstract material.
- Collaborated with service provider customers like Version and Turk Cell.
- Worked on the Visuals for VTS poster using the personas, for marketing the product., using brand guidelines.
- Produced mockups and prototypes while iterating with engineering and
- Product management to meet feature requirements for the existing product.

Ross Store Inc.

Oct 2013 - Dec 2015

Web/Visual Designer

- Researched & redesigned the intranet portal using Adobe Creative Suite & Oracle WebCenter.
- Created meaningful and compelling designs to help users become more productive and frequently visit the portal.
- Worked on design to be simpler and user-friendly from complex and abstract material.
- Collaborated extensively across departments & with various stakeholders.

^{**}Was Preparing for UX Design Course during Jan 2016 - Mar 2016.

^{**}Work samples upon request**